(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
紫咲シオン Murasaki Shion Graduation LIVE 卒業LIVE
Murasaki Shion Graduation LIVE
1. I'm Your Treasure Box
Ah... Ah... Ah... Ah... Ah... Ah... Ah... Ah...
Ahoy!
キミのことが　大好き...
I love you...
宝鐘マリン　参上！
Houshou Marine, reporting for duty!
あぁ～！キミのことが　大好き...！
Ah~! I love you...!
いっくよー！
Here we go!
Ahoy!
キミのことが　大好き...
I love you...
あぁ～！キミのことが　大好き...！
Ah~! I love you...!
紫咲シオン 卒業LIVE
Murasaki Shion Graduation LIVE
今宵も頭上では
Tonight as well, above my head
綺麗な満月がキラキラ
The beautiful full moon is sparkling
幸せそうに世界を
It's happily lighting up
照らしている
the entire world
当の私は
But as for me,
ミカヅキ
作詞・作曲 さユり
Mikazuki
Lyrics/Composition: Sayuri
出来損ないでどうしようも無くて
I'm a failure and it's hopeless
夜明け夢見ては
Dreaming of the dawn,
地べた這いずり回ってる
I'm crawling around on the ground
それでも誰かに見つけて欲しくて
Even so, I want someone to find me
夜空見上げて叫んでいる
Looking up at the night sky and shouting
逃げ出したいなぁ 逃げ出せない
I want to run away, but I can't
明るい未来は見えない ねえ
I can't see a bright future, hey
それでもあなたに見つけて欲しくて
Even so, I want you to find me
蝶のように舞い上がるの
I will soar up like a butterfly
欠けた翼で飛んだ
Flying with broken wings
醜い星の子 ミカヅキ
An ugly child of the stars, a crescent moon
ミカヅキ
Mikazuki (Crescent Moon)
今宵も頭上では 綺麗な満月がゆらゆら
Tonight as well, a beautiful full moon sways above my head
誰かの腕に抱かれて 眠っている
Sleeping in someone's arms
当の私は 独りの夜に 押し潰されては
As for me, I'm being crushed by the lonely night
誰にも見えない 夜闇這いずり回ってる
Crawling around in the darkness of the night, invisible to anyone
それでも誰にも負けたくなくて 宇宙の隅でもがいている
Still, I don't want to lose to anyone, struggling in a corner of the universe
追いつきたいや 追い越したいや 夢に見たような世界ね
I want to catch up, I want to overtake, it's a world like the one I saw in my dreams
それでも誰かと比べてばっか 周りを見ては立ち止まって
Still, I'm always comparing myself to others, looking around and stopping
欠けたものを探した そんな自分を変えたい
I searched for what was missing, I want to change that part of myself
それでもあなたと同じ景色が また見たいから
But I still want to see the same scenery as you again
泣き出したくても 投げ出したくても 諦めたりはできない
Even if I want to cry, even if I want to give up, I can't abandon it
それでもあなたに見つかるように サナギは強く手を伸ばすの
But so that you can find me, the chrysalis reaches out its hand strongly
欠けたもの抱きしめて 願いを放つよ ミカヅキ
Embracing what's missing, I'll release my wish, Mikazuki
それとも誰かに見つけて欲しくて 夜空見上げて叫んでいる
Or do I just want someone to find me, shouting up at the night sky
泣き出したいけど 泣き出さない もう後戻りなどできないね
I want to cry, but I won't, there's no going back now, right?
それでもあなたに見つけて欲しくて 蝶のように舞い上がるの
But I still want you to find me, so I'll soar up like a butterfly
欠けた翼で飛ぶよ 醜い星の子 ミカヅキ
I'll fly with broken wings, an ugly child of the stars, Mikazuki
光を放った ミカヅキ
Emitting light, Mikazuki
今宵も頭上では 綺麗な満月がキラキラ
Tonight as well, the beautiful full moon shines brightly above my head
次は君の番だと 笑っている
Smiling, as if saying it's your turn next
だれかの心臓になれたなら
If I Could Become Someone's Heart
こんな泥濘となげくだれかの 生きる理由になれるでしょうか
Can I become a reason for someone who laments this mire to live?
これは僕からいま君に贈る 最初で最後のアいの言葉だ
These are the first and last words of love I send from me to you now
街も人も歪みだした 化け物だと気付いたんだ
The city and people have begun to warp, I realized they were monsters
欲動に巣食った愚かさも 全てがこの目に映る
Even the foolishness that haunts desire, everything is reflected in these eyes
シアトリカルに手の上で 誰も彼も踊らされる
Theatrically, in the palm of a hand, everyone and anyone is made to dance
生まれた意味だって知らぬまま 形骸化した夢は錆びついてしまった
Without even knowing the meaning of being born, the hollow dream has rusted away
愛をください
Give me love
きっと誰もが望んでいた
I'm sure everyone wanted it
愛をください
Give me love
そっと震えた手を取って
Gently take my trembling hand
愛をください
Give me love
心臓を抉る
Gouging out the heart
醜いくらいに美しい愛を
A love so beautiful it's ugly
こんな泥濘となげくだれかの 生きる理由になれるでしょうか
Can I become a reason for someone who laments this mire to live?
いつか終わると気付いてから 仕上げよう僕の心臓を
After realizing it will end someday, I'll complete my heart
もう死ぬほどさ、笑ってみせてよ
Give me a smile, like you're dying to.
もしも夢が覚めなければ、姿を変えずにいられた？
If the dream hadn't ended, could I have stayed the same?
解けた指から消える温度、血を巡らせるのは誰の思い出？
The warmth fading from unclasped fingers, whose memories are circulating through the blood?
雨に濡れた肺、啜り泣く秒針、並んだ送電塔、
Lungs soaked by rain, sobbing second hands, lined-up transmission towers,
夕暮れ飛ばす停まったままの観覧車
A stopped ferris wheel against the evening sky.
机に咲く花、君の声も、何もかも、最初から無かったみたい
The flower blooming on the desk, your voice, everything, it's as if it never existed from the start.
死にたい僕は今日も息をして、
I, wanting to die, breathe again today,
生きたい君は明日を見失って
While you, wanting to live, lose sight of tomorrow.
なのになんで悲しいのだろう、リフレインするのが人間だ
Even so, why is it so sad? Humans are creatures of refrain.
永遠なんてないけど、思い通りの日々じゃないけど
There's no such thing as eternity, and days don't always go as planned.
脆く弱い糸に繋がれた、次の夜明けがまた訪れる
Connected by a fragile, weak thread, the next dawn will arrive once more.
どんな世界も君がいるなら、生きていたいって思えたんだよ
In any world, if you're there, I felt like I wanted to keep living.
僕の地獄で君はいつでも、絶えず鼓動する心臓だ
In my hell, you are always the heart that never stops beating.
いつしか君がくれたように
Just like you once gave to me,
僕も誰かの心臓になれたなら
If I could also become someone's heart.
はい！というわけで
Yes! And so...
あ？
Huh?
え？
Eh?
なんだこれ？
What's this?
ホロライブ2期生 紫咲シオンさん、
Hololive 2nd Gen Murasaki Shion-san,
至急校長室まで来てください
please come to the principal's office immediately.
えー、めんどくさーい。なんでー？
Ehh, what a pain. Why?
仕方ないですね
I guess I have no choice.
え？
Eh?
なに？
What?
わー！
Wow!
すごい！
Amazing!
なにこれ、めっちゃ綺麗！
What is this? It's so beautiful!
すご！
Wow!
シオンさん、こちらへどうぞ
Shion-san, please come this way.
YAGOOさんだ。はい
It's YAGOO-san. Yes.
卒業証書。紫咲シオン、12月8日生まれ
Graduation Certificate. Murasaki Shion, born on December 8th.
あなたは魔界学校の課程を修了しましたので、
You have completed the curriculum of the Demon World School,
ここに証します。令和7年4月26日、谷郷元昭
and I hereby certify it. April 26, Reiwa 7 (2025). Motoaki Tanigo.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
みんな見て！
Everyone, look!
もらっちゃった、卒業証書！イエーイ！
I got it, my graduation certificate! Yay!
すごい！うわ、すごいこれ
Amazing! Wow, this is incredible.
お？
Oh?
え？
Eh?
何、何？
What, what?
ほうほう、ほうほう
I see, I see.
え、まだ私に渡したいものがあるの？
Eh, you still have something you want to give me?
えー！
Wha-!
シオンさん、お疲れ様です
Shion-san, thank you for your hard work.
配信をご視聴のファンの皆様、いつも応援ありがとうございます
To all the fans watching the stream, thank you always for your support.
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
カバー株式会社の谷郷元昭です
I'm Motoaki Tanigo from Cover Corp.
お、本物だ！
Oh, the real one!
実は今回、シオンさんから質問を預かってきています
Actually, I've received some questions from Shion-san.
実は今回シオンさんから質問を預かってきています
そういえば、質問したな。
Oh right, I did ask some questions.
そういえば、なんか
Come to think of it.
免許はＭＴですか？ＡＴですか？
Is your license for Manual or Automatic?
免許はマニュアルですね。
My license is for a manual transmission.
あ、いいよー！
Oh, nice!
良かったー
Good.
他の免許はもっていますか？
Do you have any other licenses?
え、なんかあるのかな？
Eh, I wonder if there's anything else?
他は免許は持ってないです。
I don't have any other licenses.
あ、車なんだね
Ah, so just for cars.
当時なぜ私に声をかけたのか気になります！理由はありますか？
I'm curious why you reached out to me back then! Is there a reason?
え、これ気になる！どうしよう。
Eh, I'm curious about this! What if...
なんもなかったら
...it's nothing?
配信者として魅力を感じたからですね。
Because I felt your charm as a streamer.
まぁ、ちょっと、やんちゃな感じのところとかが
Well, your somewhat mischievous side and so on.
...と思いました。
...is what I thought.
当時なぜ私に声をかけたのか気になります！理由はありますか？
I'm curious why you reached out to me back then! Is there a reason?
あ、そうなんだ。そうなんだね。
Oh, I see. I see.
逆にね。
On the contrary.
今後VTuber業界、配信界隈などがどうなっていったらいいと思いますか？
How do you hope the VTuber industry and streaming world will develop in the future?
あ、これも気になるよね。
Oh, I'm curious about this too.
やはりあの、ボカロPとか歌い手さんが
Just as Vocaloid producers and singers
しっかり定着していったように、
have firmly established themselves,
ま、VTuberも、あの、これから10年とかかけて
I hope VTubers will also spend the next 10 years
しっかり職業として定着すればいいなと思っています。
firmly establishing themselves as a profession.
さすが社長っぽいこと...ぽいこと？
As expected, something like a CEO... like a CEO?
ぽいというか、社長...社長だな。
Or rather, CEO... he really is a CEO.
ホロライブの最終目的的なのはあるんでしょうか？
Is there an ultimate goal for Hololive?
そうですね、ま、日本だったり、あの、
Well, I hope that for people in Japan
世界の人たちにとって、
and around the world,
ま、ホロライブっていうものがそのVTuberを、
Hololive will become something that
ま、代表するような存在に、ま、なっていて、
represents VTubers,
ま、皆さんにあこがれていただけるような、
and something that everyone
ま、そういう存在になっていればいいなと思っております。
can look up to.
あ、世界征服かと思った、今『世界』って言ったから。
Oh, I thought you meant world domination because you said "world".
シオンさん、あらためまして、
Shion-san, once again,
今まで長い間活動お疲れ様でした。
thank you for all your hard work over the years.
最後の配信、頑張ってくださいね。
Good luck with your final stream.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました！
見てー！
Look!
みんなー！
Everyone!
谷郷社長から卒業証書もらいました！
I received a graduation certificate from CEO Tanigo!
卒業証書 紫咲シオン あなたは魔界学校の課程を修了しました
Graduation Certificate: Murasaki Shion. You have completed the Demon Realm School curriculum.
見て見て！
Look, look!
紫咲シオンって書いてあるんだよ。
It says "Murasaki Shion" on it.
裏も！
The back too!
可愛いー！
So cute!
シオンシオンになってる。
It's all Shion-y.
谷郷さん、本当にありがとうございました。
Tanigo-san, thank you so much.
いっぱい質問答えてもらっちゃって、ありがとうございました。
Thank you for answering so many questions.
え、見て！
Eh, look!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
超綺麗なんだよ。
It's super beautiful.
ほら！
Look!
上にね、あの、
Up there,
惑星とか、月とか、いっぱい付いてるの。
there are lots of planets and moons and stuff.
シオンね、銀色が好きなんだよね。
Shion likes silver, you know.
銀色が好きだから、銀色とシオンのね、あの色の紫色にしてもらいました。
So I had them use silver and my signature purple color.
超綺麗でしょ。
It's super beautiful, right?
で、先ほどライブをやったステージにも...
And, to the stage where I just performed...
行けちゃうんですね。
...I can actually go.
行きますか！
Shall we go!
ライブバージョンのステージに、チェンジ！
Changing to the live version of the stage!
おほー！
Oho!
すごい！
Amazing!
え、めっちゃ綺麗、本当に。
Wow, it's really beautiful, honestly.
三日月がね、こっちだ。
The crescent moon is over here.
綺麗。
Beautiful.
魔界学校なんだよ、これ。いや、すごいでしょ。
This is the Demon Realm School. It's amazing, right?
それでは皆さん、改めまして、
Well then, everyone, once again,
今日は紫咲シオンの卒業配信に来てくれて、本当にありがとうございます。
thank you so much for coming to Murasaki Shion's graduation stream today.
ハッシュタグはこちら！
The hashtag is here!
紫咲シオン卒業ライブで、
With #MurasakiShionGraduationLive,
たくさんポストしてください。スクショ待ってます。
please post a lot. I'm waiting for your screenshots.
トレンド1位乗ってるらしいです、ありがとうございます。
I heard we're trending at #1. Thank you!
はい、というわけで歌わせていただいた楽曲ですが、
Now, regarding the songs I just sang,
1曲目は『三日月』...
the first one was 'Mikazuki'...
2曲目は『誰かの心臓になれたら』でした。
and the second one was 'Dareka no Shinzou ni Naretara'.
みんな、どうだった？
How was it, everyone?
コメントはちょっと、たまに止まったりしてるんだけど、
The comments are freezing occasionally,
見れるかな。見てます。
but I'm trying to see them. I'm watching.
見てますけど、ちょっと...
I'm watching, but it's a bit...
タイムラグ、タイムラグなのか、これ。止まっちゃった...
Is this lag? Is it lag? It froze...
止まっちゃって、うー、めっちゃ綺麗だなってステージね、ステージ、うん。
It froze... but the stage is so beautiful, yeah.
皆そのステージの、あの、まだ次元にいるわ。
Everyone is still in the dimension of that stage.
ありがとうございます、本当に。
Thank you so much, really.
『三日月』はね、あの、1回歌ったことある曲なんですけど...
'Mikazuki' is a song I've sung once before...
思い入れがある曲なので、一番最初に歌わせていただきました。
but since I have a strong connection to it, I sang it first.
『誰かの心臓になれたら』は、
As for 'Dareka no Shinzou ni Naretara',
正直、本当、バカ高かったです。
to be honest, it was incredibly high.
高かったけど頑張って、
It was high, but I did my best.
あ、コメント見えた！
Oh, I can see the comments now!
「ずっと固まってます」って言ってる。
They're saying, "It's frozen the whole time."
うん、ずっと固まってたけど、動いたよ。今。
Yeah, it was frozen, but it moved just now.
今ちょうど動きました。
It literally just moved.
コメント、重たいよね、やっぱみんな、いっぱいコメントしてくれてるから重くなっちゃうんだな。
The comments are laggy. Since everyone's posting so much, it gets slow.
てか、めっちゃ綺麗だね、これ。
By the way, this is really beautiful.
はい、というわけでね、みんな、たくさんのコメントと、たくさんのツイート、ありがとうございます。本当に。
Anyway, thank you all for all the comments and tweets. Truly.
というわけで、この後はゲストパートになります。最後まで見ていってね！
So, next up is the guest part. Please stay with me until the end!
今なんじゃない？
Isn't it now?
メラメラとたぎる
Flaming and seething
眠っているだけの正義
Justice that's only sleeping
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even someone like me wants to be your hero
Mela!
…かっこいい君には…
...To the cool you...
…僕じゃ頼りないのかななんて
...Maybe I'm not reliable enough
そりゃそうだよな だって
Well, that makes sense, because
今もこうして迷ってる
I'm still lost like this even now
ラララ ラララ
La la la, la la la
手を取ってくれないか
Won't you take my hand?
ラララ ラララ
La la la, la la la
ギブアンドテイクさ
It's give and take
ラララ ラララ
La la la, la la la
君が僕のヒーローだったように
Just like you were my hero
今なんじゃない
Is it not now?
メラメラとたぎる
Flaming and boiling
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
The justice hidden even within me
どうしようもない 衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable impulse
ほら気付けば手を握っている
Look, I've realized I'm holding your hand
いったいぜんたい そんなに荷物を
Why on earth are you
背負い込んでどこへ行くの
carrying so much luggage and where are you going?
ねえねえ待って 僕にちょっと
Hey, wait, to me just a little
預けてみては
why not try entrusting it?
信じてばかりの僕と
Me, who does nothing but believe
信じることが怖い君と
and you, who is afraid of believing
どちらが正しいのかなんて
Which one of us is right,
誰にもわからないさ
no one can know
ラララ ラララ
La la la, la la la
僕らだけの世界
A world just for us
ラララ ラララ
La la la, la la la
ギブアンドテイクさ
It's give and take
ラララ ラララ
La la la, la la la
補い合えた暁には
When we are able to complement each other,
同じ夢を見たい
I want to see the same dream
君は隠すと苦しめて
Hiding it makes you suffer,
独りぼっちにさせたのは
and making you feel all alone
少し僕のせいなんだよな ごめんね
was a bit my fault, I'm sorry
だけど見るべきはリアルだ
But what we should look at is reality
今こそ僕が助けるんだ
Now is when I'll save you
抱えないで 信じて頼ってほしいんだ
Don't bottle it up, I want you to believe and rely on me
今なんじゃない メラメラとたぎる
Is it not now? Flaming and boiling
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
The justice hidden even within me
どうしようもない 衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable impulse
ほら気付けば手を握っている
Look, I've realized I'm holding your hand
ほっとけない そんなに荷物を
I can't leave you alone, carrying so much luggage,
背負い込んでどこへ行くの
where are you going?
ほんのちょっと 僕にちょっと
Just a little, to me just a little
預けてみては
why not try entrusting it?
こんな僕も君のヒーローに
I want someone like me to also
なりたいのさ
become your hero
ラララ ラララ
La la la, la la la
まっすぐ時計は6時
The clock points straight to six
夜空に一番星
The first star in the night sky
影をふんで夜に紛れたくなる
I want to step on shadows and disappear into the night
帰り道
on the way home
どんなに探してみても
No matter how much I search,
一つしかない星
there's only one star
何万光年離れたところから
From tens of thousands of light-years away,
あんなに輝く
it shines like that
いいな 君はみんなから愛されて
How nice, you are loved by everyone
いいや 僕は ずっと一人きりさ
No, I've always been all alone
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
星降る夜 一瞬の願いごと
A fleeting wish on a night of falling stars
きらめいて ゆらめいて
Sparkling, shimmering
ルル…エテール…シグナル…
Lu lu... Ether... Signal...
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
空見上げて指を指されるような
Looking up at the sky, like we're being pointed at
つないだ線ほどかないで
Don't undo the lines we've connected
僕がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how bright I am
もうすぐ時計は8時
The clock will soon strike 8:00
夜空に満天の星
The night sky is full of stars
何億光年離れたところには
In a place hundreds of millions of light-years away
もうないかもしれない
They might not even exist anymore
月が綺麗で泣きそうになるのは
The moon is so beautiful it makes me want to cry
いつかの日にか
Because I know that one day
別れが来るから
A farewell will surely come
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
彗星みたいな流れる独り言
My flowing monologues are like comets
消えていく残像は
The fading afterimages
真夜中のプリズム
Are prisms in the middle of the night
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
切な願い誰かに届いたら
If my painful wish could reach someone
変われるかな夜の縁を
I wonder if I can change,
なぞるようなこんな僕でも
Even for someone like me who traces the edge of the night
遥か彼方僕らは出会ってしまった
In the far distance, we ended up meeting
カルマだから何度も出会ってしまうよ
Because it's karma, we'll keep meeting again and again
雲の隙間で
Through the gaps in the clouds
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
夜広げて描こう絵空事
Let's spread out the night and paint an empty dream
暗闇を照らすような
Something that lights up the darkness,
満月じゃなくても
Even if it's not a full moon
だから集まって星座になりたい
That's why I want to gather and become a constellation
色とりどりの光放つような
Shining with many different colors
つないだ線ほどかないよ
I won't undo the lines we've connected
君がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how bright you are
天使にふれたよ！
作詞：稲葉エミ　作曲：川口進
Tenshi ni Fureta yo!
Lyrics: Emi Inaba, Composition: Susumu Kawaguchi
ねえ、思い出のカケラに
Hey, let's name these fragments of memories
名前をつけて保存
And save them
するなら「宝物」が
I think 'Treasures'
ぴったりだね
Is the perfect name
そう、心の容量が
Yes, we've spent so much time together
いっぱいになるくらいに
That our heart's storage
過ごしたね
Is almost full
ときめき色の毎日
Every day filled with excitement
馴染んだ制服と上履き
Our familiar uniforms and school shoes,
ホワイトボードの落書き
And the doodles on the whiteboard
明日の入り口に
I wonder if I really have to leave them
置いてこなくちゃいけないのかな
At the entrance to tomorrow
でもね、会えたよ！
But you know, I met one!
すてきな天使に
A wonderful angel
卒業は終わりじゃない
Graduation is not the end
これからも仲間だから
We'll be friends from now on, too
一緒の写真たち
The photos we took together
おそろのキーホルダー
And our matching keychains
いつまでも輝いてる
Will shine forever
ずっと その笑顔 ありがとう
Thank you for that smile, always
もう 桜の花びらも
Even the cherry blossom petals
ぜんぶ 散ってしまったね
Have all fallen by now
あびたい あびたい 見えない
I want to bathe in it, bathe in it, I can't see it
ゆっくりなスピードでも
Even at a slow speed
きっと
Surely
あの空は見えてたね
We could see that sky
何度もつまずいたこと
The many times we stumbled
それでも
Even so,
最後まで歩けたこと
The fact that we could walk until the end
ふわり放課後の廊下に
Softly, in the after-school hallway
こぼれた音符の羽
Spilled feathers of musical notes
ふかふか積もるまで
Until they pile up softly
このままでいれたらいいのにな
I wish we could stay like this
でもね、ふれたよ
But you know, I touched them
愛すべき天使に
Those lovable angels
ただいまって言いたくなる
It makes me want to say "I'm home"
この場所は変わらないよ
This place will never change
メールの受信箱
My email inbox
まるしたカレンダー
The circled calendar
とびきりの夢と出会い
Extraordinary dreams and encounters
くれた音楽にありがとう
Thank you for the music you gave me
駅のホーム、変わらぬ道
The station platform, the unchanging road
離れてても同じ空見上げて
Even if we're apart, we look up at the same sky
ユニゾンで歌おう
Let's sing in unison
でもね、会えたよ
But you know, I met them
素敵な天使に
Those wonderful angels
卒業は終わりじゃない
Graduation is not the end
これからも仲間だから
Because we'll always be companions
大好きって言うなら
If you say "I love you"
大好きって返すよ
I'll say "I love you" back
忘れ物もうないよね
There's nothing left behind anymore, right?
ずっと永遠に一緒だよ
We'll be together forever
いつもモノクロだった瞳の奥の
Deep within my eyes that were always monochrome
景色捨てたら夢見つけた
When I threw away the scenery, I found a dream
何もない世界で作る絆は
The bonds formed in an empty world
強い意志与えた
Gave me a strong will
裏返した
Turned inside out
日常でまた
In our daily lives once more
走ってゆく先に君はいた
You were there at the end of the road
触れた心は輝いた
The heart I touched sparkled
鮮やかな色になって
Turning into vibrant colors
羽ばたくよ希望乗せて
I'll take flight, carrying hope
無限に広がる空の下集まった
Gathered under the infinitely spreading sky
願い守り進めば
If we protect our wishes and move forward
まだ誰も知らない明日へと
Toward a tomorrow that no one knows yet
引き寄せられるように覗いた瞬間
The moment I peeked as if drawn in
光の糸は君包んだ
The threads of light enveloped you
細く千切れそうな絡まった運命
A tangled fate that seems thin and ready to break
きっとまだ変われる
Surely it can still change
間違えても信じた道は
Even if I make a mistake, the path I believed in
新しい景色を
Shows me a new scenery
A new scenery
照らすだろう
Will likely illuminate
巡る
Turning
時の中笑って
Smiling through time
様々な想い持って
With various feelings
始めよう
Let's begin
また一から
Once more from the start
辿り着いた儚い奇跡
The fleeting miracle we've reached
壊れないように
So that it won't break
手を伸ばし繋げば
If we reach out and connect our hands
ほら
Look
君は側で
You are by my side
いつまでも…
Forever...
まだ透明な私たちは
We, who are still transparent,
どんな色にでも
Into any color at all
染まることができるから
Can be dyed, so
夢叶えよう
Let's make our dreams come true
走って行く先に
Where we're running towards
君はいた
You were there
触れた
Touched
心は輝いた
Our hearts shone
鮮やかな色になって
Turning into vivid colors
羽ばたくよ
We'll take flight
希望乗せて
Carrying our hopes
無限に広がる空の下集まった
Gathered under the infinitely expanding sky
願い守り行けば
If we keep protecting our wishes
君と誓ったあの日の記憶
The memory of that day I promised you
今超えて過去から
Now overcoming it from the past
まだ誰も知らない
To a tomorrow that no one knows yet
明日へと
Forward
はい、というわけでぺこらちゃんに来てもらいました！
Alright, and so, we have Pekora-chan here with us!
来ました！
I'm here!
ぺこらちゃーん！
Pekora-chaaan!
卒業するんかい！
So you're really graduating?!
ぺこらちゃん来てくれてありがとう、卒業ライブに。
Pekora-chan, thank you for coming to my graduation live.
いやいや、シオンちゃん、むしろ呼んでくれてありがとうぺこだけど。
No no, Shion-chan, if anything, thank you for inviting me, peko.
ありがとう。一緒に「カラフル」歌えて、めっちゃ嬉しかった！
Thank you. I'm so happy we could sing 'Colorful' together!
なで「カラフル」なの？
Why 'Colorful'?
え、そう、思ったの。まどマギの曲じゃん、で二人で歌う曲だなって思って。
Well, I thought... it's a Madoka Magica song, and I felt it was a song for two people to sing.
ぺこらちゃんの声に絶対合うと思ったわけよ。
I thought it would definitely suit your voice.
おおー、ほうほう。
Oh, I see, I see.
そう、だから一緒に歌いたいなと思って、エモいし。
Yeah, so I wanted to sing it with you. It's moving too.
あ、じゃあ二人は…
Ah, so the two of us...
魔法少女ってこと？
Are magical girls?
そういうこと！
That's right!
我ら！
We are!
今日！
Today!
天下統一！
Unifying the world!
打ち取ったりー！
Have conquered it!
ヨセイトスじゃねーし！あれ魔法少女じゃねーし！
That's not Yosetosu! That's not a magical girl thing!
やめてよぺこ、魔法少女の話してたのに急にヨ…
Stop it peko, we were talking about magical girls and suddenly Yo...
いや、今、急に言ったら覚えてるのかなっていうので。
No, I just wanted to see if you'd remember if I said it suddenly.
ちゃんと覚えてるじゃん。
I remember it perfectly.
当たり前よー。
Of course you do.
何回やったと思ってんの天下統一の下り。
How many times do you think we've done the 'world unification' bit?
あ、でもそうだったんだ、そういう選曲だったんだ。ぺこら嬉しかったもん、「カラフル」好きだったから。
Ah, but I see, so that was the song choice. Pekora was happy because I liked 'Colorful'.
ぺこちゃんと「まどマギ」の曲で「カラフル」歌いたいなっていう。
I wanted to sing 'Colorful' with Pekora-chan, which is a Madoka Magica song.
もうなんか途中からぺこちゃんと一緒に歌ってて、ぺこちゃんがまどかに見えてきたもん。
While singing with Pekora-chan, you started to look like Madoka to me.
マジで言ってる？
Are you serious?
え、ちょっと待って、まどかかも…と思って。え、可愛いまどかかもって思ってきた。
Wait, I thought... maybe she is Madoka... I started thinking, maybe she's the cute Madoka.
ってことは、暁美ほむら？
So that makes you Akemi Homura?
はい。
Yes.
なんか見えてきたかも、救いたい。
I might be starting to see it, I want to save you.
ぺこらを救いたい。
I want to save Pekora.
世界線を変えたい。
I want to change the world line.
やめてくれ。
Stop it.
ぺこらを救う世界線にしたい。
I want to make it a world line where I save Pekora.
シオンは何度も…
Shion has many times...
死んで…
Died...
ぺこらを救うんだ。
To save Pekora.
重いよ！なんかむしろ逆じゃないの？
That's heavy! Isn't it usually the other way around?
シオンを救うぺこらの方がさ、いいじゃないの。なんでぺこらを救うシオンになってんの。
Pekora saving Shion sounds better, doesn't it? Why is Shion saving Pekora?
それ面白すぎるなマジで。
That's way too funny, seriously.
え、なんかさ。
Um, like...
今までさ、天下統一活動とかたくさんしてきた。
We've done a lot of 'world unification' activities and such.
ね、天下統一さ、いつやったと思ってんの。
Hey, when do you think we did that world unification thing?
天下統一、結構最近。
World unification was fairly recent.
うそ、最近だよ。だってぺこらたちの初コラボとかってもう5, 6年前とかじゃないの？
No way, it was recent. Because our first collab was like 5 or 6 years ago, right?
ちょっと冷ましてたけどさ。
It had cooled down a bit, though.
マリオカート。
Mario Kart.
ありました！
We had that!
あの頃のぺこらちゃんは、なんて初々しくて可愛かったんでしょう。
Pekora-chan back then was so innocent and cute.
今は？
And now?
今も可愛いよ。
You're still cute now.
キノコ取れなかったぺこ。
"I couldn't get the mushroom, peko."
やめてぺこ！
Stop it, peko!
「うわっ、落ちたぺこ！」みたいな感じだったのにさ。
You were always like, "Whoa, I fell, peko!"
えー、でもそう思ったらさ、シオンちゃんってマジ変わんないかも。
Well, thinking about it like that, you haven't changed at all, Shion-chan.
がー、ガチで？最初から今まで？
Re- Really? From the beginning until now?
ええ、なんか、最初からクソガキだし。
Yeah, I mean, you've been a brat since the start.
でもなんか、遊ぶたびにクソガキ感もありつつも、
But every time we hang out, while you're still a brat,
大人の部分もちゃんとあるんだなっていうのは…
I can see that you've got a mature side too.
それずっと言ってくれてるよね。
You've always said that to me.
お、ぺこらね、ずっと思ってた。
Yeah, I've always felt that way.
ずっと言ってくれてる。
You're always saying it.
そう、でもぺこらちゃんはあの時は、うん、
Right, but back then, Pekora-chan was like...
「ぺこ、うわっ、落ちたぺこ！
"Peko, whoa, I fell, peko!
わっ、シオン先輩！」
Oh, Shion-senpai!"
あー、あの時はほら、一生人見知りパターンぺこだったんでしょう。
Ah, back then, I was just in permanent shy mode, peko.
「シオンちゃん」って呼んでって一生言い続けたら、
After I kept telling you to call me "Shion-chan,"
シオンちゃんって呼んでくれるようになった。
You finally started calling me that.
ええ、確かにぺこら結構先輩とかにはさ…
Yeah, I'm usually the type to call people "Senpai"...
そう、先輩って言うタイプぺこだからさ。
Yeah, because that's just how I am, peko.
でもね、やっぱ今は言い慣れたシオンちゃんとかってすごい言い慣れたぺこだけど、
I'm totally used to calling you "Shion-chan" now, peko,
やっぱ最初のその「先輩」から「シオンちゃん」って呼び方を変える時はめっちゃ大変だった。
But changing from "Senpai" to "Shion-chan" at first was really hard.
うん、なんか頑張ってるんだろうなっていうのが、めっちゃ頑張ってるんだろうなっていうのがちょっと伝わってきて、
Yeah, I could tell you were really trying hard to do it,
なんかちょっと申し訳ないなって思ってたんだけど、
And I actually felt a little bad for you,
なんか乗り越えてくれた。頑張りを乗り越えてシオンちゃん定着したから。
But you pushed through it. You made "Shion-chan" stick.
いやそう、もうこれからもシオンちゃんって呼んでいくからね、ぺこらは。
Yeah, I'm going to keep calling you Shion-chan from now on too.
そうだね。最近でもね、天下統一活動してきて…
That's right. We've been doing our "Tenka Toitsu" activities lately...
今もね、天下統一活動中なんだけどさ。
We're actually in the middle of it right now.
そうだよ。天下統一開催しながらね。
That's right. While we're holding our unification.
ええ、そうだよ、シオンちゃんが卒業したとしても
Yeah, even if Shion-chan graduates,
天下統一は永久活動中だから、天下は統一してくからこれからもね。
Tenka Toitsu is forever, and we'll keep unifying the world from now on.
これからもね。あ、最近もね、色々天下統一してきたよね。
From now on. We've unified a lot of things lately, haven't we?
何だっけ？
Like what?
「何だっけ？」じゃねーよ！
Don't ask me "Like what!"
もう何かねーのかよ、一つくらい。
Can't you think of even one thing?
もう早鞆（はやとも）ね。
Well, there's Hayatomo.
ああ、早鞆ね。あとは？
Oh, right, Hayatomo. What else?
あとは…
And...
『Color-full』歌ったね。
We sang "Color-full."
それそれそれそれ！今や、今さっきや、もう。
That's it! We just did that! Like, right now.
確かに、でも色々ライブとかでいっぱい歌ったもんね。
True, we've sung a lot together at various lives.
そうだよね、ライブとかでもいっぱい歌ったし、
Yeah, we've performed together a lot,
ぺこらたち結構さ…結構活動してきたよ。
We've really... done quite a lot together.
5年前だよ、初コラボ。
Our first collab was five years ago.
5年…え、5年！？
Five years... Wait, five years!?
え、何年デビューして？6年目？
How many years since debut? The sixth?
今6年目、7年目なんだよ。
It's the sixth, heading into the seventh now.
長い！マジで言ってる？
That's so long! Are you serious?
そうなんだよ。長いよね。
It's true. It's been a long time.
長いけどさ、ぺこら今日シオンちゃんに伝えたいことがある。
It has, but Shion-chan, there's something I want to tell you today.
何？
What is it?
ちょっと待ってて。
Just wait a second.
え、何何？
Wait, what's going on?
ぺこら…待って。
Pekora... Wait.
今日…嘘でしょ！
Today... You're kidding me!
シオンちゃんと…
With Shion-chan...
シオンちゃんが今日卒業してしまうということで、手紙を書いてきたぺこ。
Since Shion-chan is graduating today, I wrote a letter, peko.
びっくりしたでしょう。
Surprised?
びっくりした。ガチで知らなかったでしょう。
I am. I really had no idea.
しかもガチで書いてる…え、見ないで！
And you actually wrote it... Hey, don't look!
ええ、マジで知らなかった。嘘。
Wow, I really didn't know. No way.
じゃあ、ちょっと読ませてもらいます。
Well then, I'll read it now.
シオンちゃんへ。
Dear Shion-chan.
はい。
Yes.
ヤッホー。もう卒業か。
Yahoo! You're graduating already.
ヤッホー、いるそれ？それいる？
The "Yahoo!"? Was that necessary?
寂しいよ。
I'm lonely.
「何で辞めちゃうんだよ」って言っても困らせるだけだと思うので、
I know asking "Why are you leaving?" would only trouble you,
ぺこらがシオンちゃんに思ってることを伝えようと思います。
So I want to tell you how I truly feel about you.
うん。
Yeah.
シオンちゃんと初めてコミュニケーションを取ったのは、
The first time we ever talked was
ぺこらがホロライブに入った時にシオンちゃんからDiscordで声を掛けてくれたのが最初だったよね。
when you reached out to me on Discord right after I joined Hololive.
懐かしいね。
How nostalgic.
ぺこらは人見知りすごかったから、
I was incredibly shy back then,
先輩から声を掛けてもらえることがとても嬉しかったぺこ。
So I was so happy that a senpai spoke to me, peko.
ええ、良かった。
Aw, I'm glad.
そこから色々なコラボをして、子供っぽいところもありつつも、
Since then, we've done so many collabs together. You're childish sometimes,
しっかりと大人の部分もあるし、先輩なのに話しやすいし、
but you have a mature side too. Even as my senpai, you're so easy to talk to,
遊んでて楽しい、そして何より優しいシオンちゃんが大好きです。
fun to be around, and above all, so kind. I love you, Shion-chan.
う、ありがとう。
Oh, thank you.
恥ずかしいな…ありがとう。
This is embarrassing... thank you.
ユニバ旅行もシオンちゃんだから行けたんだと思う。
I think I was only able to go on that USJ trip because it was with you.
知らなかったクレーンゲームの上手さや気遣い屋さんのところ、
Seeing your hidden talent for claw machines and how considerate you are,
ここでは話せないこともたくさん話せた旅行だった。
and sharing things I can't talk about here made it a trip to remember.
うん、たくさん話したね。
Yeah, we talked about so much.
今度はどこへ行こうか。
Where should we go next?
正直、卒業すると聞いた時はびっくりしつつも、
To be honest, I was shocked when I heard you were graduating,
どこかで腑に落ちる自分もいて、
but a part of me also understood.
残り少ない時間でたくさんの思い出を一緒に作りたいなと思いました。
I wanted to make as many memories as possible in the time we had left.
作れたかな？
Do you think we did?
作れたよ。
We did.
作れたよね。いっぱい天下統一したもんね。
We definitely did. We unified a lot of things together.
卒業はとても寂しいし、悲しいけど、
Your graduation is so lonely and sad, but...
ぺこらとシオンちゃんの関係は…
The relationship between Pekora and Shion-chan is...
天下統一は、永久不滅！
Tenka Touitsu is eternal!
はい！
Yes!
それじゃあ、本当に、最後の挨拶をしますよ！
Then, let's do the truly final greeting!
はい！
Yes!
我ら！天下統一！
We! Tenka Touitsu!
せーの！うしさとーり！
One-two! Ushisatori!
シオンちゃん大好きだぞー！
I love you, Shion-chan!
ありがとうぺこちゃーん！
Thank you, Peko-chan!
じゃあ、まだ多分このあとも卒業ライブがあると思うから、
Well, I think there's probably more of the graduation live after this,
頑張ってね！
so do your best!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
これ、あとで渡すから。
I'll give this to you later.
え？
Eh?
読みますあとで。
I'll read it later.
ありがとうぺこちゃーん！
Thank you, Peko-chan!
じゃあねシオンちゃん！またねー！
Bye Shion-chan! See you!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
マジかよ。
Seriously?
気分次第です僕は 敵を選んで戦う少年
I'm a boy who fights by choosing his enemies depending on my mood
魁！アスノヨゾラ哨戒班
Charge! Asu no Yozora Shoukai-han
作詞・作曲：Orangestar
Lyrics/Comp: Orangestar
叶えたい未来も無くて 夢に描かれるのを待ってた
With no future I wanted to fulfill, I waited to be drawn into a dream
そのくせ未来は怖くて 明日を嫌って過去に願って
And yet, I'm afraid of the future, hating tomorrow and wishing on the past
もうどうしようもなくなって叫ぶんだ 明日よ明日よもう来ないでよってそんな
I became helpless and screamed, "Tomorrow, tomorrow, don't come anymore," such a
僕を置いて 月は沈み陽は昇る
Leaving me behind, the moon sets and the sun rises
けどその夜は違ったんだ 君は僕の手を
But that night was different, you [took] my hand
空へ舞う 世界の彼方 闇を照らす魁星
Dancing to the sky, beyond the world, a pioneer star illuminating the darkness
君と僕もさ また明日へ向かっていこう
Let's head toward tomorrow again together, you and I
夢で終わってしまうのならば 昨日を書き換えて
If it's going to end in a dream, rewrite yesterday
なんて言わないから また明日も君とこうやって笑わせて
I won't say that, so let me laugh with you like this again tomorrow
あれから世界は変わったって 本気で思ったって
Since then, even if I seriously thought the world had changed
期待した世界が鼻突いたって 未来は残酷で
Even if the world I expected was annoying, the future is cruel
それでもいつだって きっと見ていた世界は本当に綺麗だった
Even so, whenever, surely the world I saw was truly beautiful
忘れてないさ 思い出せるようにしまってんの
I haven't forgotten, I've stored it away so I can remember
君がいてもいなくとも 飛べるなんて妄想
Thinking I can fly whether you're here or not is just a delusion
独り歩くことさえ僕は
Even walking alone, I...
しないも藍色の風に 吐いた幻想
A fantasy exhaled into the deep blue wind
壊してくれって願って もがいたって
Wishing for it to be destroyed, even if I struggle
願ったんなら叶えてしまえよって
"If you wished for it, fulfill it,"
君は言って
You said
また明日の夜に 会いに行こうと捠が
Even if I struggle to go meet you again tomorrow night
愚かな君はいないかな それでも今でも僕ら一つだから
I wonder if the foolish you isn't there... but even now, we are one
またねと言おう 笑って言おう 未来もずっと君といたいから
Let's say see you, let's say it with a smile, because I want to be with you forever in the future too
叫ぼう 今の日をいつか思い出す 未来の僕ら
Let's scream, for our future selves who will remember this day
はーい！ということでね。
Hi! So.
いやー、次のゲストなんですが…
Well, the next guest...
ちょっとハードルが高そうなんだよねー。
The hurdle seems a bit high.
めちゃめちゃ名高い魔導書には、
In a very famous magic book,
召喚される人が喜ぶものを捧げると成功するって書いてあったんだけど…
it said that if you offer something that the person being summoned would like, it will be successful...
やるしかない。
I have to do it.
磨いとこ。
Let's brush.
よし！はい！
Okay! Yes!
さあ、出てこい！
Now, come forth!
わああああ！
Waaaah!
えっ、シオン先輩！？
Eh, Shion-senpai!?
本当に出た！
It actually worked!
待って、待って！
Wait, wait!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
本当に帰ってこれて...
I'm so glad I'm back...
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ほうが思ってたのと違うかも...
This might be different from what I imagined...
もうすぐお尻に届きそう...
It's almost reaching my butt...
きもっ！きもすぎる！
Gross! Too gross!
逃げないで！逃げないで！
Don't run away! Don't run away!
へー...
Heh...
本当に...
Really...
本当にさ...
Seriously...
うーん、ちょっと見せてちょっと。
Hmm, let me see it for a bit.
おっほい、どうぞ！
Whoops-a-daisy, here you go!
ちょっと立って立って立って。
Stand up, stand up, stand up.
え？
Eh?
もう、あとで全部見せてあげるのに...
Geez, I was going to show you everything later...
何ですか何ですか？どこが気になるんですか？
What is it, what is it? What part are you curious about?
あ、でも沙花叉...
Ah, but Sakamata...
か、これは本当に沙花叉。
This... this really is Sakamata.
ま、見た目は沙花叉っぽいよね。
Well, you look like Sakamata.
もちろん！
Of course!
ちょっと、きもすぎるか。
Wait, is it too gross?
いやいやいや！
No, no, no!
失敗した可能性があるな、これ。
I might have failed this summoning.
お忘れですか？
Did you forget?
沙花叉を。
About Sakamata?
え？
Eh?
沙花叉はこんなもんですよ。
Sakamata is just like this.
何だ...
What...
何を夢を抱いてるんですか？
What kind of dreams were you harboring?
きもかったか？きもかったか？
Was I gross? Was I gross?
そう、そうだよね、そうだよね。
Right, that's right, that's right.
そうですって。最初からきもかったか。
Exactly. I've been gross from the start.
あ、沙花叉だ。
Ah, it's Sakamata.
沙花叉。
Sakamata.
お久しぶりです！
Long time no see!
元気してた？
How have you been?
会いたかったから呼んでくれたんですよね？
You called me because you wanted to see me, right?
そ、う、まあまあまあ...
Well, yeah, sort of...
すっごく会いたかったみたいで。
Seems like you really wanted to see me.
そうだよ、そう。会いたかったよ。
That's right, yeah. I wanted to see you.
めちゃめちゃ元気もらえました。
I feel so energized.
あの歯ブラシこれから使いますので。
I'll be using that toothbrush from now on.
沙花叉、何で歯ブラシで召喚されたの？
Sakamata, why were you summoned with a toothbrush?
え？
Eh?
いや、多分なんですけど...
Well, I think...
シオン先輩の匂いがしたと思ってここに来たので。
I thought I smelled Shion-senpai, so I came here.
やっぱり本能かなと、はい。
I guess it was instinct, yeah.
え、あ、匂いしたんだ、歯ブラシから。
Eh, ah, so it smelled? From the toothbrush.
しました、しました。臭かった。
It did, it did. It was smelly.
いや、最高ですよ。
No, it's the best.
あ、口開けていただいたら鼻突っ込めますから、全然。
Ah, if you open your mouth, I can stick my nose in, totally.
最悪だ...
The worst...
きもいな。今日もきもさマシマシだね。
Gross. You're extra gross today as well.
沙花叉のね、卒業ライブの時も...
During Sakamata's graduation live too...
結構きもいお願いがいっぱいされたんだけど。
I was asked to do quite a lot of gross things.
いや、最高でしたね、あれはあれで。
No, that was great in its own way.
変わらない、変わらない感じがして、うん。
You haven't changed, it feels consistent, yeah.
良かった本当。
I'm glad, really.
良かった、変わらない愛情ね。
I'm glad, that unchanging affection.
ね？
Right?
あ...
Ah...
そう言われた。
You said it.
シンプルに引いちゃった。
I'm simply put off.
何でだ、何でだ。でも沙花叉も元気そうで良かったよ、シオン本当に。
Why, why. But I'm glad Sakamata seems well too, Shion, really.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
会えて良かった。
I'm glad we could meet.
ということでありがとうございました。
And with that, thank you very much.
ちょっと待って！
Wait a minute!
ん？
Hmm?
せっかく来てくれたんだから...
Since you came all this way...
え、もうこれでいいってこと？
Eh, so this is it?
え、いや、嬉しいですよ。
Eh, no, I'm happy.
また呼んでください！
Please call me again!
待って待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait!
延長戦とかで...
Maybe for an encore...
待って！「また」って何？「また」って。
Wait! What do you mean by "again"? "Again"?
シオン卒業するんだけど。
Shion is graduating, you know.
ちょっ、待って、待って！
Hey, wait, wait!
あはは、じゃないんだよ。あはは、じゃないんだけど。
Don't just laugh. It's not a laughing matter.
いやちょっと、せっかく来てくれたんだから...
I mean, since you came all this way...
一緒に歌おうよ。
Let's sing together.
え、え？
Eh, eh?
もうちょっと何か...
Maybe a bit more like...
本当に、あの、切羽詰まる感じで...
Really, like, in a desperate way...
「一緒に、一緒がいい！」って。
Say "Together, I want to be together!"
「一緒じゃなきゃ嫌！」って言ってもらえます？
Could you say "I hate it if we're not together!"?
何、何か何だろうな...
What... what's with that...
沙花叉の卒業ライブの時、シオン結構あの、頑張ったと思うんだけど。
During Sakamata's graduation live, I think I worked pretty hard.
えー、シオン先輩楽しかったです、ありがとうございました！
Ehh, Shion-senpai, that was fun, thank you so much!
待って待って！沙花叉、沙花叉！
Wait, wait! Sakamata, Sakamata!
一緒がいい！
I want to be together!
よし、きた！
Alright, there it is!
行きますか！
Shall we go!
そして、歌おう！
And then, let's sing!
やったー、歌ってくれるって！
Yay, she says she'll sing!
歌いましょう！
Let's sing!
ということでね。
And so.
はい。
Yes.
それでは聴いてください。
Now then, please listen.
スパークル！
Sparkle!
スパークル
作詞・作曲 野田洋次郎
Sparkle
Lyrics & Composition: Yojiro Noda
まだこの世界は
Still, this world
僕を飼いならしてたいみたいだ
Seems like it wants to keep me tamed
望み通りだろう
Just as you'd hoped, right?
美しくもがくよ
I'll struggle beautifully
互いの砂時計
Our hourglasses
眺めながらキスをしようよ
Let's kiss while gazing at them
「さよなら」から一番遠い
The furthest from "Goodbye"
場所で待ち合わせよう
Let's meet at that place
ついに時は来た
Finally, the time has come
昨日までは序章の序章で
Until yesterday, it was just the start of the prologue
飛ばし読みでいいから
It's okay to just skim read
ここからが僕だよ
From here on, it's about me
経験と知識と
With experience and knowledge
カビの生えかかった勇気を持って
And a courage that's started to get moldy
未だかつてないスピードで
At a speed never seen before
君のもとへダイブを
I'll dive towards you
まどろみの中で 生温いコーラに
In a daze, with a lukewarm cola
ここでないどこかを夢みたよ
I dreamed of somewhere that wasn't here
教室の窓の外に
Outside the classroom window
電車に揺られ運ばれる朝に
In the morning as I'm carried, swaying on the train
運命だとか未来だとかって
Words like fate or future
言葉がどれだけ手を伸ばそうと届かない
No matter how far they reach, they can't get to
場所で僕ら恋をする
The place where we fall in love
時計の針も二人を
The hands of the clock too
横目に見ながら進む
Continue forward, watching us from the corner of their eye
こんな世界を二人で一生
Let's live through this world, the two of us, for a lifetime
いや、何章でも
No, for however many chapters it takes
生き抜いていこう
Let's live it through
はじめましてなんてさ
Things like "Nice to meet you"
遥か彼方へと追いやって
Let's push them far, far away
千年周期を一日で息しよう
And breathe a thousand-year cycle in a single day
辞書にある言葉で
With the words found in a dictionary
出来上がった世界を憎んだ
I hated the world they created
万華鏡の中で
Inside a kaleidoscope
八月の或る朝
A certain morning in August
君は僕の前で
In front of me, you
はにかんでは澄ましてみせた
Smiled shyly and then looked coolly away
この世界の教科書のような笑顔で
With a smile like a textbook for this world
嘘みたいな日々を
Days that felt like a lie
規格外の未来を
An extraordinary future
悲劇だっていいから望んだよ
I wished for them even if they were a tragedy
そしたらドアの外に君が全部抱えて立ってたよ
And then you were standing outside the door carrying it all
運命だとか未来だとかって
Words like fate or future
言葉がどれだけ手を伸ばそうと届かない
No matter how far they reach, they can't get to
場所で僕ら遊ぼうか
The place where we should play
愛し方さえも君の匂いがした
Even the way I loved smelled like you
歩き方さえもその笑い声がした
Even the way I walked sounded like your laughter
いつか消えてなくなる
Of your everything that will
君のすべてを
One day disappear
この眼に焼き付けておくことは
Keeping it burned into my eyes
もう権利なんかじゃない
Is no longer just a right
義務だと思うんだ
I think it's a duty
運命だとか未来だとかって
Words like fate or future
言葉がどれだけ手を伸ばそうと届かない
No matter how far they reach, they can't get to
場所で僕ら恋をする
The place where we fall in love
時計の針も二人を
The hands of the clock too
横目に見ながら進む
Continue forward, watching us from the corner of their eye
そんな世界を二人で一生
Let's live through that world, the two of us, for a lifetime
いや、何章でも
No, for however many chapters it takes
生き抜いていこう
Let's live it through
Oh...
時ノ雨、最終戦争
作詞・作曲：Orangostar
Rain of Time, Final War
Lyrics/Composition: Orangostar
答えて　ねぇ
Answer me, hey
にわか雨が寄せる街の夜へ
Into the city night where a sudden shower approaches
沈む世界　感覚　そこ
A sinking world, at the bottom of sensation
きっと僕ら生まれながら
Surely we, since the moment we were born
何処にもないコタエを探してる
Have been searching for an answer that exists nowhere
応えて　ねぇ
Answer me, hey
叶えて　何を
Grant me... what?
今日の世界はいかがです
How is today's world?
きっと言われずとも君は
Surely even without being told
君を知っているだろうとも
You already know yourself
けどまだ信じられぬだろう
But you probably still can't believe it
終わる日々の果て
At the end of these closing days
泣きだした空の彼方
Beyond the sky that started to cry
終わらない善と悪の祭典
A never-ending festival of good and evil
なんてざま期待もないなって
What a mess, I have no expectations
君は君をかき消した
And you erased yourself
時の流れに希望さえ
In a world where even hope
描けない世界で
Cannot be drawn in the passage of time
正しさなんて誰にもわかんないから
Because no one knows what's right
君は何を願ってもいいの
It's okay for you to wish for anything
いいの
It's okay
コタエは無いよ
There is no answer
僕のことなどきっと僕はまだ
About me, surely I still
悲しさの木霊する
Echo with sadness
孤独の中遠く浮かぶ
Floating far away in loneliness
昨日は...
Yesterday was...
今日で世界は終わります
The world ends today
君が拒めどその暮れに
Even if you refuse, in that twilight
咲かせ死に花
Let the flowers of death bloom
成るは厭なり想いは成らず
It becomes pitiful, thoughts do not come true
君の全てはね
Everything about you, you see
止まない憂いの最中
In the midst of unending sorrow
二つ感情は対を成して
Two emotions form a pair
願いを放つ君は覚えてるかな
And release a wish. Do you remember,
あの日涙の意味を
The meaning of the tears that day?
この世はまだ終わらない
This world is not over yet
明けぬ夜か今日咲いてたって
Even if the night doesn't end and today blooms
僕は書き換えじゃないって
That I'm not a replacement
咲く雷　空が晴れる
The thunderous sky clears up
泣き止んだ今日にさらば
Farewell to today when the crying stopped
変わらない想いを振り翳すように
I will live as if brandishing
生きていく　泣きながらでいいさ
My unchanging feelings. It's okay to cry,
それを繰り返して笑える生涯
Repeat it for a lifetime you can laugh at
また明日の雨に打たれたって
Even if you're hit by tomorrow's rain again
いつかこの世に生まれてきて
So that someday you'll be able to say
良かったって言えるようになるから
You're glad you were born into this world
その日まで
Until that day
負けないよ
I won't lose
ただ声一つ
作詞・作曲：MIMI
Just One Voice
Lyrics/Composition: MIMI
続く時間の欠片を
Collecting fragments
集めている
Of continuing time
ただ過ぎるノートの
Writing in the blank space
余白に書く
Of a notebook that's just passing
答えは...
The answer is...
...ほんのり小さな感情へ
...towards a slightly small emotion.
愛をひとつ　またね　またね
One love, see you again, see you again.
夜に咲く温度と灯るまで
Until the temperature blooming in the night lights up.
呼吸ひとつ　生きる　生きる
One breath, living, living.
優しい日々の横で泣かぬように
So as not to cry by the side of gentle days.
嗚呼...
Ah...
泣かぬように
So as not to cry.
ちっちゃな言葉　チクチクしたの
Tiny words, they prickled.
キリがないけどさ　それを
There's no end to it, but those...
忘れたフリ　疲れたよ
Pretending to forget, I'm tired.
夜よ　抱きしめて
Oh night, hold me tight.
今日だって笑う笑う
Even today, laughing, laughing.
泣いちゃう僕を隠すために笑う
I laugh to hide the me who's about to cry.
言えないことは言えないで良いって思えたら
If I could think it's okay not to say the things I can't say...
軽くなれるのかな
...would I feel lighter?
愛をひとつ　またね　またね
One love, see you again, see you again.
夜に咲く温度と灯るまで
Until the temperature blooming in the night lights up.
呼吸ひとつ　生きる　生きる
One breath, living, living.
優しい日々の横で泣かぬように
So as not to cry by the side of gentle days.
愛をひとつ　またね　またね　嗚呼
One love, see you again, see you again, Ah...
愛をひとつ　またね　またね
One love, see you again, see you again.
優しい日々の横で笑うように　嗚呼
So as to laugh by the side of gentle days, Ah...
吐き出す気持ちは簡単でも
Even if spitting out feelings is easy...
生きるの難易度高すぎて
...the difficulty level of living is too high.
どうにも解けない問いだらけ
Full of questions that can't be solved anyway.
さっぱりきっぱり前向いてなんて
Looking forward clearly and firmly...
しなくて良いから抱きしめて
...you don't have to do that, so just hold me.
愛をひとつ　またね　またね
One love, see you again, see you again.
はい、というわけで、ゲストパートとソロパートでした！
Yes, and so, that was the guest part and the solo part!
どうでしたか？
How was it?
ゲストパートはね、メル、おかゆと、ころねと、歌いましたね、まず一曲目。
For the guest part, I sang with Mel, Okayu, and Korone, the first song.
から始まって、「星座になれたら」白上フブキ、フブキちゃんと、すいちゃんが来てくれました！
Starting from that, for "If I Could Be a Constellation," Shirakami Fubuki, Fubuki-chan, and Sui-chan came!
「天使にふれたよ！」で船長と歌って、
We sang "Tenshi ni Fureta yo!" with Sencho,
「カラフル」をぺこちゃんと歌いました。
And sang "Colorful" with Peko-chan.
いやー、シオン、ぺこちゃんとのMCをやったんだけど、
Man, Shion, I did an MC with Peko-chan,
まさか手紙を読んでくれると思わなくて、
But I never thought she'd read a letter for me,
正直、本当にあの、ビックリが勝っちゃって、
Honestly, really, the surprise just took over,
「えっ、手紙書いてきてくれたの？」ってなって、
I was like, "Eh, you wrote me a letter?"
ちょっと「えっえっ、本当にえっ？」みたいな感じのまま感情のままだったから、
While I was still like "Eh? Eh? Really? Eh?" I was just full of emotion,
ちょっと驚きを隠せなかったんだけど、
So I couldn't hide my surprise.
いや、本当に嬉しい、今ちょっとウルッとね、あの、聞いてて思いました。
But I'm really happy, listening to it just now made me a bit teary-eyed.
そう、ぺこちゃんと「カラフル」歌って、MCにも出てもらいました。
Yeah, I sang "Colorful" with Peko-chan, and she also appeared in the MC.
で、「アスノヨゾラ哨戒班」も二期生で歌いました。
And we also sang "Night Sky Patrol of Tomorrow" with the 2nd generation.
集まってくれてありがとな。
Thanks for gathering.
えー、で、「スパークル」を、沙花叉クロヱ、沙花叉と一緒にね、スパークルを歌いました。
And then, I sang "Sparkle" together with Sakamata Chloe, Sakamata.
いやーねー、まあ成功するかちょっとわかんなかったんですけど、
Well, I wasn't sure if it would succeed,
魔法が成功したみたいで、召喚されてきてくれました、歯ブラシで。
But it seems the magic worked, and she was summoned... with a toothbrush.
「また、またいつでも呼んでくださいね」とか言ってたけど、卒業ライブなんだ、こっちは。
She said, "Please call me again anytime," but this is a graduation live.
ガチ卒業するんだわ。
I'm seriously graduating.
はい、沙花叉ありがとうね、来てくれて。
Yes, Sakamata, thanks for coming.
で、ソロ曲の「時ノ雨、最終戦争」と「ただ声一つ」、二曲連続で歌わせていただきました。
And then I sang my solo songs "Toki no Ame, Saishuu Sensou" and "Tada Koe Hitotsu" back-to-back.
どうだったでしょうか。
How was it?
手紙ね、いや手紙本当にビックリしたね。
The letter, man, that letter really surprised me.
そう、沙花叉もね、本当に、みんなビックリしてたわ。ビックリした？
Yeah, Sakamata too, really, everyone was surprised. Were you surprised?
ビックリしてそうだなー。
Looks like you were.
ありがとうね、とか、今めっちゃコメント見てんだよ。
Saying "Thank you" and all, I'm looking at the comments right now.
コメント早すぎてさ、見れねーよ。早すぎるよ、コメント。
The comments are too fast, I can't see them! Too fast!
「行かないで」...いい、卒業します。
"Don't go"... it's fine, I'm graduating.
というわけでね、あと二曲となりました。
And so, there are only two songs left.
次に歌う曲なんですが、実はこの配信をするにあたり、
The next song... actually, in doing this stream,
何を最後にみんなに伝わったらいいかなっていうのを考えてたんですよ。
I was thinking about what I wanted to convey to everyone at the end.
その中で、実はホロライブの公式ページにあるシオンのプロフィール...
In that process, I looked at Shion's profile on the official Hololive page...
ホロライブ公式ページのプロフィールって何だよっていう人がいっぱいそうだけど
A lot of people probably wonder what the profile on the Hololive official page is...
実はあのプロフィール書いてある人、結構書いてあるから、なんか好きな食べ物とか誕生日、身長とかの下に
Actually, for those who have it written, it's quite detailed. Underneath things like favorite food, birthday, height...
「夢」っていう欄が実はあるんですよ。ある人とない人がいるかもしれないんだけど
There's actually a column for "Dream". Some might have it, and some might not.
実はその夢のところにシオンが書いた言葉があるんだけど、「世界のみんなを笑顔にする」なんですよね。
In that "Dream" section, there's a phrase I wrote: "Make everyone in the world smile."
まあ、でも世界のみんなとまではちょっと難しいかもしれないけど
Well, making *everyone* in the world smile might be a bit difficult...
せめてシオンのことを好きでいてくれる人には絶対笑顔でいてほしいと思ったから
But I at least want those who like me to definitely be smiling.
そんな気持ちで次の曲を歌いたいと思ってます。
With those feelings, I want to sing the next song.
それでは聴いてください。「メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレット」
Please listen: "Mage of Violet."
暗い表情ばっか見てないで ウダパパパラリラ 踊れよ
Don't just look at gloomy expressions, uda-pa-pa-pa-ra-ri-ra, dance!
長い顔する優等生 華やかなわがまま讃えよ
Long-faced model student, praise the glamorous selfishness!
いないいないばあでこっち向いて 狡猾な未来を咲かせよ
Peek-a-boo, look this way, make the cunning future bloom!
次第愛待って高まって 黙ればはまって黒魔術
Wait for love and it'll grow. If you're silent, you're trapped in black magic.
聖の墓地に集えよ 闇に震えけるBellos
Gather in the holy cemetery, Bellos shivering in the dark.
刹那響く言葉は ブチギレ発狂パラダイス
The words echoing for a moment are, "furious madness paradise!"
キラリ心奥底まで届け これからも私のそばで
Sparkle, reach the depths of your heart. Stay by my side from now on too.
不思議な力打ち放って 世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Unleash mysterious power, and let the whole world smile.
ウダパパパラリラ歌えば 一生一緒だよべべ
If we sing uda-pa-pa-pa-ra-ri-ra, we'll be together forever, bebe.
暗いモノばっか背負わないで 生温かさらば踊れよ
Don't just carry dark things, say goodbye to lukewarmness and dance!
視界外目逸らさないで 今はただ離れてかないで
Don't look away, just don't leave me right now.
ヤンヤ舞ってあっち向いて 今はまだ心の準備を
Dance wildly and look that way, I'm still preparing my heart.
期待サイズで固まって ウダパパ動け黒魔術
Freeze in the size of expectation, uda-pa-pa, move, black magic!
我に続け今宵よ 闇を破れメシアよ
Follow me tonight, break through the darkness, Messiah!
移れ希望その名は 眠りの発症パラダイス
Pass on the hope, its name is, "onset of sleep paradise!"
キラリ心奥底まで届け 白黒つけてあげるから
Sparkle, reach the depths of your heart, because I'll settle this for you.
不思議な力振りかざして みんなで笑顔になっちゃって
Wield mysterious power, and let everyone smile.
ウダパパパラリラ歌えば 一生一緒かもね
If we sing uda-pa-pa-pa-ra-ri-ra, maybe we'll be together forever.
ヒラリヒラリと紫に染まって これからもあなたのそばで
Fluttering, dyed in violet. By your side from now on too.
奇跡の呪文解き放って 咲かせる笑顔の花を
Release the miracle spell, making the flowers of smiles bloom.
キラリ心奥底まで届け これからも変わらないままで
Sparkle, reach the depths of your heart. Staying just as we are from now on.
不思議な力ほら宿して 世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Look, mysterious power dwells within, and let the whole world smile.
ウダパパパラリラ歌えば 一生一緒だよべべ
If we sing uda-pa-pa-pa-ra-ri-ra, we'll be together forever, bebe.
絶対一生一緒だよべべ
We'll absolutely be together forever, bebe.
はい、というわけでメイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレットでしたー！
Yes, and that was "Mage of Violet"!
歌う前にもね、話したんだけど「世界のみんなを笑顔にする」ということで
I mentioned it before the song too, about "making everyone in the world smile."
特大魔法を使っちゃいました！見てましたか？
So I used a super large-scale magic spell! Did you see it?
ほら！虹がかかって晴天です！
Look! A rainbow appeared and the sky is clear!
みんなが笑顔になってると嬉しいなと思います。
I'll be happy if everyone is smiling.
というわけで、次が最後の曲になるんだけど、その前にこうやってみんなの前で話すのも、いや...
And so, the next one will be the last song. But before that, talking in front of everyone like this... well...
今日が最後になると思うから、お手紙を書いてきました。
Since I thought today would be the last, I wrote a letter.
では、読みます。
Well, I'll read it.
塩っ子のみんなへ。
To all the Shiokkos.
いよいよ今日は卒業ライブ当日だね。
The day of the graduation live is finally here, isn't it?
ギリギリの心境を書きたくて、伝えたくて、
I wanted to write and convey my feelings at the very last moment,
今日で言う昨日、卒業ライブ前日に書いてる...
so I'm writing this yesterday, the day before the graduation live...
やばい、もう泣いてきちゃった。まだ全然話してないのに。
Oh no, I'm already crying. Even though I've barely started talking.
正直、まだちょっぴりふわふわしたような不思議な気持ちです。
To be honest, I still have a slightly fluffy, strange feeling.
今日卒業ライブを終えて、スタジオを出たら、実感するのかな。
I wonder if it'll sink in once I finish the graduation live today and leave the studio.
家に帰ったら、実感するのかな。
Will it sink in when I get home?
卒業したんだって、思うのかな。
Will I realize that I've graduated?
今は悔いのないようにやり切りたいという気持ちでいっぱいです。
Right now, I'm just filled with the desire to give it my all so I have no regrets.
7年目、活動期間は6年半、こんなにも長い期間をずっと一緒に歩んでくれたこと、
Entering the 7th year, with 6 and a half years of activities, for walking together with me for such a long time,
本当にありがとう。
thank you so much.
休止したりして、たくさん待たせてしまったりして、本当にごめんなさい。
I'm really sorry for taking breaks and making you wait so much.
辛い思いをさせてしまったなって、ちょっと心残りです。
It's a bit of a regret that I made you feel sad.
塩っ子のみんなに見てほしいから、いろんなこと頑張りたいなって思う中で、体調を崩してしまったり、
I wanted all the Shiokko to see me, so while I wanted to work hard on various things, I ended up getting sick,
会社はどんどん大きくなって、それに対応していくのも、なかなか難しくて、
the company kept growing, and it was quite difficult to keep up with that,
精神面や体調は悪くなる一方で悔しかったです。
and I felt frustrated as my mental and physical health only got worse.
自分のことなんてどうでもいいし、壊れたらそれでいいと思ってた私ですが、
I used to think that I didn't matter and it was fine if I broke down,
長い期間を経て、みんなのおかげで、少しでも自分を大切にしてあげたいと思うことができるようになりました。
but after a long time, thanks to everyone, I've come to want to cherish myself even a little bit.
これは、普通の人にとっては、当たり前のことなのかもしれないけれど、
This might be something obvious for ordinary people,
私にとって本当にすごいことなんだよ。
but for me, it's something truly amazing.
みんなのおかげです。いつもたくさん愛を伝えてくれてありがとう。
It's all thanks to everyone. Thank you for always giving me so much love.
形として届けてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for delivering it in various ways.
出会ってくれてありがとう。
Thank you for meeting me.
見つけてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for finding me.
心から感謝でいっぱいです。
I'm filled with gratitude from the bottom of my heart.
ホロライブで過ごした思い出は、ずっと忘れません。
I will never forget the memories I made in Hololive.
ホロメン、支えてくれる運営さん、そして塩っ子のみんなと出会えて、本当に幸せでした。
I was truly happy to have met my fellow Hololive members, the staff, and all the Shiokko.
ずっと、大好きです。
I will always love you.
紫咲シオンは、死ぬわけではありません。
Murasaki Shion is not going to die.
私という存在がいたこと、覚えてくれたら嬉しいなって思います。
I'd be happy if you could remember that I existed.
私もみんなのこと絶対に忘れないからね。
I'll never forget all of you either.
6年半、本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for these six and a half years.
最強の魔法使い、紫咲シオンより。
From the strongest mage, Murasaki Shion.
というわけで、昨日、昨日、お手紙を書きました。
So, I wrote a letter yesterday, yesterday.
本当はもっと早く書こうかなって思ったんだけど、どんな気持ちになってるかなと思って
Actually, I thought about writing it earlier, but I wondered what kind of feelings I'd have,
ギリギリで書いたほうがみんなに伝わるのかなと思って、ギリギリに書きました。
and I thought it might reach everyone better if I wrote it at the very last minute, so I did.
いや、ちゃんと伝わってると嬉しいです。
Well, I hope it's getting through to you.
みんなが幸せになってくれることを願ってます。
I hope everyone will be happy.
泣いちゃったよ。くそ。
I ended up crying. Damn it.
それでは、次が最後の曲になりますが、ちょっとその前にお水飲んできます。
Now, the next one will be the last song, but before that, I'm going to drink some water.
いや、ちょっと、思った通りにいかないな。
Well, things aren't quite going as I expected.
というわけで、
So,
最後、
lastly,
この曲を、
this song,
大切に、
dearly,
シオン
作詞・作曲・編曲：じん
Shion
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Jin
真っ赤な夕空 青くなる星
A crimson sunset sky, stars turning blue
心臓を焦がして 冷めない温度
Burning the heart, a temperature that won't cool down
半端に零した声の残響と
With the echoes of a voice half-spilled
半端に混ざった花の色
And the color of flowers half-mixed
きっと立ち止まって芽を伸ばしたって
Surely, even if you stop and let the buds grow
咲いた瞬間 散ってしまうのでしょう
They'll probably scatter the moment they bloom
いっそそれも素敵な景色なんだって
If only I could have thought that it was also a wonderful scenery
きっとそんな風に思えたら良かったんだって
that it was also a wonderful scenery
言えない
I can't say it
「さよなら」なんて
Something like 'goodbye'
まだ言えないまま 魔法が解けていく
Without being able to say it yet, the magic is fading away
バラバラになって 花になって 風に溶けていく
Falling apart, becoming flowers, dissolving into the wind
手を振れないまま 黙って立っている
Standing silently without being able to wave
私を連れて
Take me along
私を忘れて
Forget me
連れて すぐに
Take me away, quickly
伝えたい想いを声に出したって
Even if I were to voice the feelings I want to convey,
こんな言葉なんて言えないんだろう
I probably couldn't say such words.
大事に思ってしまうからずっと
Because I treasure them so much, I've always
大事なことが伝わらないんじゃないかって
worried that the most important things wouldn't get across.
知らない
I don't know,
I don't know.
知りたくもないことばっかで 胸が裂けていく
With so many things I don't even want to know, my heart is tearing apart.
ズタズタになって 痛いくらいに 愛しくなっていく
Being torn to shreds, it starts to hurt as I love you even more.
手も触れないまま 不確かにしてしまう
Leaving it uncertain, without even being able to touch your hand.
ごめんね ごめんね
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
いつか 時間が経ってみたら
If some time passes,
なんでもないって顔をして
I'll put on a face as if it's nothing.
寂しさも 痛みすらも 抜け落ちて過去になる
Both the loneliness and even the pain will fall away and become the past.
いつしかそんな日が来たら そんな時が来るなら
If such a day comes eventually, if such a time comes,
だったら今は
then for now...
どうしようもないくらいに 君を想っている
I'm thinking of you so much that I can't help it.
思い出になんて ならないくらい 君で出来ている
So much that it won't even become a memory, I'm made of you.
ずっと気づいてた 気づいてしまったんだ
I've always known, I've finally realized it.
「忘れて」なんてね
To say "forget me"...
嘘だ
...was a lie.
愛しさが 胸を焦がしていく
This love is burning my heart.
傷になったって 覚えていて 忘れないでいて
Even if it becomes a scar, please remember, please don't forget.
もう言えないから 今、愛を伝う
Because I can't say it anymore, I'll convey my love now.
笑って また会おう
Let's meet again with a smile.
さようなら
Goodbye.
みんな本当に、本当に、めっちゃ大好きだ。
Everyone, really, really, I love you so much.
最後まで見てくれて本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for watching until the very end.
この6年半、約7年、応援してくれてありがとう。
Thank you for supporting me for these six and a half years, nearly seven years.
ずっと見てくれてありがとう。
Thank you for always watching.
ずっと愛してくれてありがとう。
Thank you for always loving me.
バイバイ！またね！
Bye-bye! See you again!